here at this time and talked about how
important it is to to turn the page and
get ready for for what's ahead and the
challenges that go with that. Honestly,
it's a similar message today. The
biggest difference is the record. And
they were way different, but the message
should still be similar each and every
year as you're going through it and the
process you go through to get there. So
whether you kick ass and throw a hell of
a year or not nearly enough wins, uh the
only carryovers I really want are the
lessons that you want to take, you know,
from that season and don't repeat them
again. And uh there are plenty for us.
But uh as it begins, there's a there's a
cool part to this process. We had free
agency meetings last week now here and
doing a lot of the interviews in the
evenings. Um there's a lot of cool
things that start during this week and
envisioning, you know, what parts of
your team could look different, you
know, by adding some of the players. So,
all that said, glad to get rocking with
you guys and uh we'll go through it all.
>> Coach, I know you're a supporter of
emerging players. How much do you lean
on mental health?
>> Yeah, it's a big deal. And I think um
like first off it's like heartbreaking
to hear, you know, about Rondelle. Um
but I'm hopeful that we get to a point
that we're not talking about mental
health just when a tragedy hits, but
that we're talking about it on a regular
basis. Then we know we're making real
strides in that.
One of the things from the NFL
standpoint, the advancements we've made
is in player engagement and knowing that
each team, you know, has a full team
there ready to help and support and put
those resources into effect. But, uh,
that would be that would be my, you
know, my hope that we're talking about
it way more than just, you know, when
tragedy, you know, takes place.
John. Yeah, I think one of the things I
really respect from their team like an
identity and uh those are things that
you know can stand the test of time and
last. I thought um like just when you're
playing his teams through the years is
going to be a tough game and uh the
attitude the style of the team players
may change you know and they did you
know through the years but I thought the
identity of John stayed consistent even
though scheme may change offensively how
they would do things I think that's like
the mark of a really good coach
>> yeah isn't that awesome to have Mike
back in in Pittsburgh of all places. Um
it's such a cool thing. He has such
pride of being from Pittsburgh. And so
any of us that know Mike, we've all
heard, you know, Pittsburgh stories. But
I think it's fitting for him uh to go
there because when I think of Mike, I
think of discipline. I think of
toughness. I think of things that like
we were talking about Harbaugh that
stand the test of time in coaching. And
I got to see that firsthand, you know,
with Mike and what that looks like on a
regular basis of really high standards,
not letting it slip. And u he's going to
do great things there. It's fantastic
organization. I thought that's just a
great fit for Mike and for Pittsburgh.
>> Championship.
>> Well, we we did a lot of digging to
start off. And so the first piece of
that, we've had some staff changes that
we've went through and although those
are difficult, there's also a lot of
excitement that comes with that. How
we'll feature the players, what things
would be different. And then the first
thing you want to do from a player
standpoint, obviously we evaluate our
own team on the roster, how we feature
them, who are free agents and then the
whole next process begins free agency
around the league and then through the
draft. So you just don't want to miss
one step of those. Um the first step for
that was on the coaching side, then it
goes in, excuse me, then it goes into
your own team and then free agency and
then finally onto the draft. So, it
takes the full process to get there and
go through that. And then as you get
into the spring and training camp,
putting your team together and creating
standards like we talked about earlier,
that's why I love coaching honestly is
putting that the puzzle pieces in the
right spots to go make that happen. Um,
we've got a lot of heavy hitters on this
roster and I can't wait to get back to
work with them.
>> We're close, Nikki. We're um I would say
probably a day or two away from like all
the way finalizing, but um yeah, for the
most part it's uh it's pretty intact and
we've had good meetings with the
coaches. They've begun that process. We
had a week last week where a lot of it
was devoted to free agency, but it's
been nice to see David and Donte and the
staffs, you know, kind of build their
connection as they're talking through
systems together. There's some good
energy that comes from that because
you're actually starting at the
beginning to say, "Well, this is why
we're going to call this this and this
is how we want to play this." And so, I
like that feeling of what that is and I
like, you know, what I'm seeing so far
from them.
Yeah, it matters a lot because um that
ability to affect the QB, it's one of
the biggest tenants in winning the game,
you know, for obviously like, you know,
scoring and that, but the ability to hit
and pressure the quarterback. Um it also
forces takeaways. Those are like things.
So, you want to see somebody that has
demonstrated speed and initial quickness
to beat somebody on the field. And I
think that can be one thing as we get
into this week and you hear timings and
that, hey, man, let's go back to that
demonstrated speed on the field and play
making ability. And so, that at the top
is what I see. But, um, beating somebody
to the punch, um, having an explosive,
you know, get off to to make someone
feel like overwhelmed. That's what all
the great rushers have.
>> Yes. And uh it's it's keeps gaining uh
momentum and strength and it's one of
the things I love about coaches act
because what we once did you know 10
years ago is different than how we do
things today where analytics was just
called statistics and we use those in
certain ways and now that's you know
grown as much and how do we simulate
models for game management? how can we
simulate um in-game practice, you know,
models to show coaching down in
distances, different personnels, points
of the game. So, yeah, I think it's
going to continue to grow and it is one
of the fun parts of the job.
especially having two young
>> Yeah. And I think it starts with Adam,
you know, wanting to be collaborative
with the coaches and the coaches also
being able to deliver the information
that, you know, Adam and the scouts need
as well. And so there's nothing the
college scouts who are on the road at
the schools, at the games live, uh, they
start the entire process and drive so
much of it. And so the coaches get to
come in and add a vision of what the
player could become in our system. And
so there's definitely a blend that I
think takes place from
the better the scouts and the coaches
connect and know one another, the easier
it is for them to see how they would fit
into the offense and the defense. And so
that's why through this spring um
there's some important processes to go
through um with both coordinators,
coaching staff, scouting staff uh to
keep encouraging that dialogue, you
know, amongst each other.
>> When you do that, is that something
that way.
>> Yes.
From my first time um being in the NFL,
I was at the San Francisco 49ers and
that was my first experience into that.
When you were a college coach, you did
the recruiting and you looked at it and
so um I would say a number of the people
there taught me what excellent could
look like in pro football. Uh a guy by
the name of Bill McFersonson who had
been a coach and was the pro director at
that time. talking about DPRs. That time
I didn't know what that was and how
would you feature a player or you know a
short yardage fullback and how different
players help the roles and how they go
to win. And so since that time I've been
much more interested in what a player
can do and how would we feature them
than the traits of things that they
don't have. And I think that's where it
all comes together as opposed to what a
player can't do is what can they at the
very highest level? What makes them so
unique and excellent? and try to put
them in those spots as often as you can.
>> Yes, it definitely has already started.
I would say
um well, you know, how I'm structuring
my own time I think is a big piece of
that too, Ben.
um as we're going through the spring, as
we're getting into training camp, those
are other things that you'll see some
differences that, you know, that would
feel, you know, differently for me and
for the players. So, there's a lot that
I'm going into. Um, and the systems and
the processes that we're going through.
I've actually started that before it was
the end of season evaluations, then the
UF, you know, the free agency process.
So, I've tried to implement as many of
those as I could um to make sure I'm
hitting all of those at the highest
level that I can.
I don't think it's changed the way you
evaluate, but I do think um there's a
different perspective of them coming in
with their first paycheck. You know,
that was a question years ago, what are
you going to get or when you have this
signing bonus? And so, the fact that
some of that's already taking place, uh
there's actually a little less of that
for the player when they come, you know,
to your organization right away. So in
some ways there's some advantages um
that I feel it's interesting to hear the
different spots along the ways why the
guys transfer was it opportunity or um
for more playing time or you know a
financially you know better scenario for
themselves and hearing those stories are
helpful but the evaluation piece has
stayed consistent. It does help that you
now can even see them in a different
system. Okay, what was he playing here?
What was that the year prior? How would
that look like? And so having different,
you know, connection points to that, I
think that does help.
>> No. Um, that's their choice, but I think
the part that does like I always come
back to is like what's that demonstrated
tape look like? And the workouts help,
but sometimes even for here, obviously I
haven't seen all the players yet, so the
interview portion and getting to know
them without any bias, sometimes that
can help. and then I'll write something
down that they said, "Okay, is that
real? Is that accurate?" And I'll follow
up on that. But I do
like when I see them do that for the
movements in there and between here and
pro days, we'll see that. But I think at
the end it still comes down to like
their football performances.
Yeah, it's a big topic and um earlier we
were talking about um you know the
mental health not just when you know a
tragedy or in this case that you're
referring to is when an injury takes
place but making sure how's the ball
player doing also and more importantly
like how's the man doing knowing that
you do feel isolated and separate from
the team in those spaces and So, I can't
speak for everyone else, but for my own
spot, I want to check on them first to
see how they're dealing with the injury,
dealing with the surgery, you know, cuz
on the swing when it's getting closer,
that's easier because then there's
something close to back to returning to
play. When it's the initial parts of it
and knowing I'm staring at six weeks,
eight weeks the entire season, those are
harder conversations and you just want
to make sure they're checking in. And
so, I love even during this time,
although
It's lonelier, but having the players
who can do their rehabs in the building,
I like it selfishly because I get to see
them and check in and see how they're
doing. Um, and everybody's got their own
process to do that, but it's very
important.
>> Yeah. Well, I'd say featuring Ben in the
ways, you know, that he can do his
things. It's in the back field. It's,
you know, through like to compare him to
Zack. They're way different skill sets,
you know, so like I know they're both
playing tight end, but you know, they're
featured differently in that way. And so
what I do know is him on the move and
whether it's run game, pass game,
running away from people, maybe not
finding the zone and stopping, those are
differences. And uh I'm looking forward
to to seeing that this year.
>> Yeah.
Yeah, super proud of Chris. I thought um
the development, you know, that he made
um and playing alongside of Laramie, I
thought a couple things that jump out to
me, John, I thought like the combination
blocks with the two of them, these are
strong people that could move people off
the line of scrimmage. And then I
thought because of Chris's athleticism,
the things that showed up the most to me
is him and pass protection. And so
having the ability to to mirror somebody
to stay in front, those were the things
that I saw week after week from Chris.
Um it's not easy that spot back up back
up, but to see that time for him to
develop um you know, I thought that was
a big deal and something I'm proud of
him for sure.
>> Yes. But we're going through the whole
process like everybody counts in that,
you know, not the same, but everybody's
part of it. But uh yeah, definitely
somebody that like obviously we're
keeping close to tabs on as Adam and his
team are going through that.
I already know.
>> I think the versatility will help in
some of that, Nikki. Um what's so much
fun about coaching Don? He's big enough
to be a 34 end. You guys saw some of
that here early on. Um he's got the
strength that can play inside at nose
tackle and quickness to move. So to see
JK and he and Johnny and how do we
feature them on the field together some
um having the three of those together
that excites me honestly. These are guys
that really love to battle and compete
and so because they're versatile uh it
gives Dante even more options of you
know how to deploy and how to match up
guys. So it's a big deal for us.
I think it's it drives um like
competition and connection. That's what
drives me. Um from the game, you know,
from when I started playing, the
connection, being on a team, I've been
on over 70 of them in my life of teams
and I've always felt that's when I'm at
my best. And then I love the competition
whether it was football, other sports to
go. But that's the thing that has always
driven me uh why I wanted to get from
playing even into coaching. It's uh it's
the connection and the competition.
>> All right. Thanks.
>> All right. See you guys.